

Giulio Carducci

Computer Engineer

I am a passionate Computer Engineer with a strong interest for emerging technologies and scientific research, which I had the opportunity to discover during my academic studies. I face everyday problems with a positive mindset and attitude towards learning new things. In my free time I enjoy hiking and practicing photography.

giulio.carducci@protonmail.com

Torino

in linkedin.com/in/giuliocarducci

(+39) 334 5909666

GiulioC.github.io

github.com/GiulioC

WORK EXPERIENCE

R&D Software Engineer Synapta

04/2018 – Present Torin.

Synapta works in the public procurement domain by aggregating all the italian public contracts in one place.

- Implemented and integrated several NLP solutions to enrich the knowledge base with additional data
- Devised machine learning and NLP strategies for out-of-core computation on huge data volumes
- Backend development of several APIs and other website features
- Configured and monitored main servers and services based on data redundancy and high-availability principles
- Main QA analyst of the website contrattipubblici.org

Reasearch Fellow for the Academic Project REPOSUM

Università degli studi di Torino

06/2018 – 06/2019 Toring

I won a 1-year research grant to study a corpus of philosophical PhD theses using NLP and Machine Learning techniques.

- Studied and leveraged semantic features of documents for different learning and representation purposes
- Feature extraction with bag-of-words, NER and NEL approaches
- Application of supervised and unsupervised machine learning techniques to different types of data

Internship

Cognitive Systems Group (CoSy)

04/2015 – 09/2015 University of Bremen I worked for 6 months as a researcher for a european project involving several countries and institutions.

- Camera movement estimation based on detected motion in scene
- Studied and Implemented different methods for face detection and face recognition of people in the movie domain
- Trained custom shapes and object detectors from images

EDUCATION

M.A. in Computer Engineering Politecnico di Torino

Politecinco di Torino

09/2015 - 04/2018 99/110

 Thesis: "Semantic Analysis to Compute Personality Traits from Social Media Posts".

B.A. in Computer Engineering Università degli Studi dell'Aquila

09/2011 – 03/2015 102/110

 Thesis title: "Design, implementation and exploitation of a database to support an embedded face recognition system".

SKILLS

Python	
Natural Language Processing	
Machine Learning	
PostgreSQL	
Linux and System Administration	
Problem Solving	• • • • •
Teamwork and Communication	• • • • •
Creativity	

PUBLICATIONS

TwitPersonality: Computing Personality Traits from Tweets using Word Embeddings and Supervised Learning

Giulio Carducci, Giuseppe Rizzo, Diego Monti, Enrico Palumbo, Maurizio Morisio. MDPI, 2018.

Semantically Aware Text Categorisation for Metadata Annotation

Giulio Carducci, Marco Leontino, Daniele P. Radicioni, Guido Bonino, Enrico Pasini, Paolo Tripodi. Italian Research Conference on Digital Libraries (IRCDL), 2018.

Modeling the Semantics of Structured Sources with Steiner Trees and Relational Graph Convolutional Networks (under review)

Giuseppe Futia, Antonio Vetrò, Giulio Carducci, Davide Allavena, Juan Carlos De Martin, Journal of Web Semnatics (IEEE Xplore), 2019.

CERTIFICATES

IELTS 7.5 (CEFR C1) (2016)

British Council

Machine Learning by Andrew Ng (2016)

Соигѕега

LANGUAGES

INTERESTS

Photography Outdoor Sports

Sustainable Development